Bryan Oyloe

Westminster, CO 80234 | 561-315-6778 | boyloe@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a 9+ year background in Petroleum Engineering. Previous positions include Drilling Fluids Specialist based in North American land drilling operations. Possess strong skills in collaboration and project management. Current app project is seeking to streamline inventory management for personnel in remote working environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Javascript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Node/Express, MongoDB, Postgres, C#, Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ExpungeColorado - In Progress

A web app designed to filter users seeking to obtain free legal counsel in order facilitate sealing their criminal records so that minor offenses are not reflected in background checks.

- Utilizes React.js with an embedded Google form to collect user responses and determine eligibility
- Collecting demographic data on users and stored in a TBD database for client statistical purposes
- Building app with all volunteer developers through Code for Denver partnership network

Oyloe Inventory Management Software Github | Demo

Mobile app designed to allow field personnel to directly input chemical inventory usage on a smart-phone or tablet eliminating the need for paper tally records and greatly improving efficiency and reportability.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Applied Node Express and MongoDB to create a NoSQL database to store information server-side
- Employed React Native with Typescript to build out a strongly typed, component based UI/UX
- Included React Native Elements for styling and Formik for controlled forms

Fat Stocks - Github | Demo

Fat Stocks is a dashboard app that allows the user to log into their page and view up to date stock quotes, company information, recent news, and historical data about the company's stock performance.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Applied Node Express and Postgresql to create a user database to store information server-side
- Utilized React.js to build out a component based UI/UX
- Incorporated React Bootstrap and CSS to customize the design of the user interface

Puzzler - Github | Demo

A WebGL browser based jigsaw puzzle game. Takes photos and cuts them up into a custom online jigsaw puzzle.

- Designed a jigsaw puzzle game using the Unity game engine
- Implemented game logic scripts with C#
- Utilized C# to design drag and drop system for puzzle pieces

EXPERIENCE

Newpark Drilling Fluids

Drilling Fluids Specialist II

Denver, CO 07/2018 - 04/2020

- Submitted daily drilling fluid reports to rig personnel summarizing current operations and drilling fluid properties along with cost saving recommendations for treatment
- Facilitated stuck pipe removal of a directional tool, saving client \$3M in replacement cost
- Utilized a team-oriented approach while working with multiple contractors on rig locations
- Performed solids analysis, alkalinity, chloride content, and fluid rheology on active drilling fluids to determine the optimal treatment plan
- Displayed organizational ability by maintaining accurate inventory of onsite chemicals and charging operators according to daily chemical usage

Newpark Drilling Fluids

Williston, ND

Drilling Fluids Specialist I

03/2013 - 02/2015

- Maintained oil-based drilling fluids to optimize drilling rate and safety
- Created calcium chloride/sodium chloride brines while drilling production laterals to ensure formation stability while minimizing loss of production
- Completed monthly safety training and testing per company policy to maintain a zero accident record on location
- Drilled fastest production lateral for QEP Resources in the Bakken region in 2014 saving the operator \$1M+ in drilling costs

MI-SWACO/Schlumberger

Williston,ND

Drilling Fluids Engineer I

08/2011 - 08/2012

- Performed fluids analysis daily for 3-4 drilling locations to deliver optimal rates of penetration for operators
- Composed daily reports for operators with treatment recommendations and service costs utilizing software to maximize efficiency and minimize cost to clients
- Visited multiple rigs after hours due to lost circulation, stuck pipe, gas kicks, etc. to ensure safety of personnel during hazardous operations
- Controlled fluid weight during hazardous wellbore pressure incursions to ensure rig personnel safety

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Denver, CO

11/2020

University of North Dakota

Grand Forks, ND

08/2018

B.S. in Petroleum Engineering

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Society of Petroleum Engineers

08/ 2015 - Present

Code for Denver 10/2020 - Present